A Guide to the 1930-1999
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
- Alphabetical Files 1935-1994
  - Virginia Union Honorary Degree, n.d. (Box 127)
  - Virginia Women in History, n.d. (Box 127)
  - Virginia Wesleyan College, 1999 (Box 127)
  - Vision of Stratford, n.d. (Box 127)
  - Volunteerism: Key to Democracy, 1995, 1998 (Box 127)
  - Volunteerism: The Ultimate Freedom, 1978-1988 (Box 127)
  - VUU Alumni, 1989 (Box 127)
  - VUU Correspondence, 1988 (Box 127)
  - VUU Fund Letter, 2000 (Box 127)
  - VUU Master plan, n.d. (Box 127)
  - VUU Fund raising Campaign, 1988 (Box 127)
  - VUU Wilder Library, 1998-1999 (Box 127)
  - VUU Wilder Issue, 1998 (Box 127)
  - VUU Simmons, S. Dallas, 1990, 1998 (Box 127)
  - VUU Retreat, 1999 (Box 127)
  - VEFC, 1998 (Box 127)
  - Virginia Performing Arts Foundation, 2001 (Box 127)
  - Warner, Mark, n.d. (Box 127)
  - Waste Disposal, 1993-1997 (Box 127)
  - Washington Lee University, n.d. (Box 127)
  - Washington Lee speech, n.d. (Box 127)
  - Washington Lee, 1998-2004 (Box 127)
  - Westminster, 1992-2004 (Box 127)
  - Westmorland 1999-2003 (Box 127)
  - "Why is Christmas Important?" 1978 (Box 127)
  - Winchester Green, 1997 (Box 127)
  - Women's Club, 1997-2005 (Box 127)
  - Woodrow Wilson Birthplace, 2001-2003 (Box 127)
  - World Affairs, 1996-2003 (Box 127)
  - YWCA Advisory Board, 2004 (Box 127)
  - YWCA Advisory Board, 2002-2003 (Box 127)
  - Ashworth, Dr. John Sheridan and Toni, 1996, 200-2001, 2004 (Box 128)
  - Bailes, Jeannie, 1996 (Box 128)
  - Bangor, Vicountess Sarah, 1997, 1998, 2000 (Box 128)
  - Bannard, Gassie and David, n.d. (Box 128)
  - Brand, Tina and Michael, 2000, 2002 (Box 128)
  - Bradly, John Thomas Jr., 1980, 1988 (Box 128)
  - Bradley, William 1991 (Box 128)
  - Burton, Stanley, 2004 (Box 128)
  - Brain, Joseph III, 1980 (Box 128)
  - Burrus, Robert L. Burrus,2002 (Box 128)
  - Byrd, Hon. Harry Jr. 1951,2004 (Box 128)
  - Cabell, James Branch Library Associates, 2005 (Box 128)
  - Campbell, Ben, 2004 (Box 128)
  - Charity Family Life, 2002-2004 (Box 128)
  - Cheek Endowments, n.d. (Box 128)
  - Cheek Memorial, n.d. (Box 128)
  - Clinton, Ms. Catherine, 2000Coates, Peter, n.d. (Box 128)
  - Cooper, Dr. William E. 1988-2003 (Box 128)
  - Cornforth, Mrs. Stauli, 1989, 1999-2001 (Box 128)
  - Corington, Jane, n.d. (Box 128)
  - Cowles, Jane and Don, n.d. (Box 128)
  - DSF, n.d. (Box 128)
  - Dementi, Wayne, 2001 (Box 128)
  - Dunn, Keith, 1999 (Box 128)
  - Foster, Carmen, 2001 (Box 128)
  - Friddell, Guy, 1990 (Box 128)
  - Gallagher, Dr. Gary, 2000 (Box 128)
  - Glasgow, Ellen, 1999 (Box 128)
  - Hager, Maggie and John, 2002 (Box 128)
  - Hall, Franklin, 2000-2003 (Box 128)
  - Hall, Lee, 2004 (Box 128)
  - Harris Family, 2002-2003 (Box 128)
  - Helftrich, Jane, n.d. (Box 128)
  - Hetherungton, Lelly and Bob, 1990 (Box 128)
  - Hill, Oliver W., 1999, 2001 (Box 128)
  - Hitz, Mary Baford, n.d. (Box 128)
  - Holton, Linwood and Jinks, 1991 (Box 128)
  - Hopkins, Evans, 1999-2002 (Box 128)
  - Holderess, Lord and Lady, 1999 (Box 128)
  - Horsley Family, 2004 (Box 128)
  - Hotchleiss, Farris P., 1988, 1996, 2001 (Box 128)
  - Hutcheson, Rossie Carter, 2000 (Box 128)
  - Johnson, David, 2001-2004 (Box 129)
  - Book Reviews, 2002-2003 (Box 129)
  - VHS, David Johnson, 2002-2003 (Box 129)
  - Johnson, David, 2001 (Box 129)
  - Johnson, David, n.d. (Box 129)
  - Johnson, David, 1987, 2000-2001 (Box 129)
  - Johnson, Nessa Baskerville, 2001-2002 (Box 129)
  - Jones, Chris, 2003 (Box 129)
  - Kaine, Timothy, 1998, 2001-2002, 2004 (Box 129)
  - Locke, Doris Jean, n.d. (Box 129)
  - Layton, Dr. William, 1988-1989, 1992 (Box 129)
  - Layton, Dr. William, n.d. (Box 129)
  - Layton, Dr. William, 2000 (Box 129)
  - Lee, Everett, 2000 (Box 129)
  - Lewis, Suzanne, n.d. (Box 129)
  - Lewis, Sydney and Frances, 1999 (Box 129)
  - Loupassi, Manoli, 2001 (Box 129)
  - Mayrts, Bill and Judith, 2000 (Box 129)
  - McCabe, Mimi Harris, 2001 (Box 129)
  - McDowell, Charlie, 1994 (Box 129)
  - McGuier, Alice and Mac, 2003 (Box 129)
  - McGuire, Hunter Holmes, 2003 (Box 129)
  - McIntyre, Mary Beth, n.d. (Box 129)
  - McPherson, Adleine, n.d. (Box 129)
  - Neil and Sarah Bell, 1999 (Box 129)
  - Pollard, Albert, 2001 (Box 129)
  - Pollard, Childe, n.d. (Box 129)
  - Price, Carol and Ted, n.d. (Box 129)
  - Queen, Noer, 1999-2003 (Box 129)
  - Quigg, H. Gerald, 2004 (Box 129)
  - Robb, Senator, 2000 (Box 129)
  - Robertson, Wyndham, 1997-2004 (Box 129)
  - Sachs "Uncle Paul", 1975 (Box 129)
  - Sadat, Mine Jehan, 1995-1999 (Box 129)
  - Scott, Buford, 1995, 1998, 2004 (Box 129)
  - Toney, Ronald, 1997 (Box 129)
  - Slatton, James, 2002 (Box 129)
  - Trani, Eugene, 1999-2001 (Box 129)
  - Wilder, Douglas, 2000-2004 (Box 129)
  - Wisdom, n.d. (Box 129)
  - Woooten, Jane Pendelton, 2000-2004 (Box 129)
  - Wyrick, Connie and Pete, 1999 (Box 129)
  - Album containing a scrapbook of award notices, compiled and assembled by Courtenay Sr. and Jr., August 12, 1993 (Box 130)
  - The American Institute of Architects, Honorary Membership, May 1999 (Box 130)
  - The American Institute of Architects, Services to Architecture Medal (In red box with unknown pin), October 12, 1991 (Box 130)
  - Association of Fundraising Professionals, Lifetime Achievement in Philanthropy Award (Plate shaped plaque), November 14, 2001 (Box 130)
  - Bar Association of the City of Richmond, Honorarium, May 1, 1991 (Box 130)
  - Better Housing Coalition, Invitation to, and photographs of the Grand Opening of the Mary Tyler McClenahan Child Care Center, August 14, 1993 (Box 130)
  - Hollins College, Doctor of Humane Letters, honoris causa, May 16, 1993 (Box 130)
  - Housing Opportunities Made Equal (H.O.M.E), Fair Housing Special Award (Marble), October 13, 1983 (Box 130)
  - Local Initiatives Support Corporation, Plaque in recognition of support, 1997 (Box 130)
  - The National Equity Fund and the Local Initiatives Support Corporation, Plaque on recognition of leadership, n.d. (Box 130)
  - National Muscular Sclerosis Society, Trophy (Round glass trophy that stands upright), n.d. (Box 130)
  - The National Society of the Sons of the American Revolution, Good Citizenship Medal (Medal with ribbon), n.d. (both Bronze and Silver medals) (Box 130)
  - The Order of the Pine, Pig and Peanut, Honorarium, April 17, 1985 (Box 130)
  - Partners for Livable Communities, Bridge Builders Award (Large black pedestal with medal citation fastened to the top), December 3, 2002 (Box 130)
  - Richmond Community Development Alliance, Community Visionary Award (Obelisk mounted on a pedestal), October 18, 2000 (Box 130)
  - Richmond LISC (Local Initiatives Support Corporation), Plaque in recognition of leadership, June 14, 1999 (Box 130)
  - Sir Robert Boyle Society of the College of William and Mary, (Gold pin), n.d (Box 130)
  - S.R.O. Housing of Richmond, Plaque thanking MTCM for her generous support of the New Clay House S.R.O., n.d. (Box 130)
  - St. Christopher's School, Plaque in appreciation of support given to The Endowment Campaign for St. Christopher's School, October 26, 1990 (Box 130)
  - Stygar Group, Inc. Southern Civility, 2003 (Box 130)
  - Style Weekly, Richmonder of the Decade, 1990 (Box 130)
  - The Task Force for Historic Preservation and the Minority Community, Preservation Award, 1983 (Box 131)
  - University of Richmond, Citation, May 12, 1985 (Box 131)
  - Urban League of Greater Richmond, Lifetime Achievement Award (Clear circular disc), 25 May 1999 (Box 131)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University, Doctor of Humane Letter, honoris causa, May 22, 1993 (Box 131)
  - Virginia Community Development Corporation (VCDC), Recognition and Appreciation, June 1996 (Box 131)
  - The Virginia Council on the Status of Women, 1st Annual VA. Women's Hall of Fame (pyramid shaped trophy), n.d. (Box 131)
  - Virginia Council on the Status of Women Celebrates, Women's History Month and the 1st Annual Virginia Women's Hall of Fame (Poster), n.d. (Box 131)
  - The Virginia League for Planned Parenthood, Honorary Member of the Board of Directors, May 19, 1983 (Box 131)
  - The Virginia League for Planned Parenthood, Outstanding Service Award (Stained glass logo mounted on a pedestal), n.d. (Box 131)
  - Virginia Theological Seminary, Lettie Pate Whitehead Evens Award, 1999 (Box 131)
  - Virginia Union University, Doctor of Humane Letters, honoris causa, May 11, 2002 (Box 131)
  - Washington and Lee University, Doctor of Humane Letters, 1983 (Box 131)
  - Accident - Kindnesses - 1938 (Box 132)
  - Adler Dinner - November 27, 1985 (Box 132)
  - Birth and Babyhood - 1917 (Box 132)
  - To the head of fine arts, college of William and Mary - 1938-1939 (Box 132)
  - Living in Williamsburg - 1938-1939 (Box 132)
  - Christmas Cards - 1940-1945 (Box 132)
  - Dr. Douglas Southall Freeman, 1927-1930 (Box 132)
  - Dr. Douglas Southall Freeman,1933 (Box 132)
  - Dr. Douglas Southall Freeman, 1934 (Box 132)
  - Dr. Douglas Southall Freeman, 1935 (Box 132)
  - Dr. Douglas Southall Freeman, 1936 - 1937 (Box 132)
  - Dr. Douglas Southall Freeman, 1938 -1939 (Box 132)
  - Dr. Douglas Southall Freeman, 1942 - 1945 (Box 132)
  - Dr. Douglas Southall Freeman, 1947 and n.d. (Box 132)
  - Dr. Douglas Southall Freeman Birthplace - 1968 (Box 132)
  - Dr. Douglas Southall Freeman Clippings - 1934, 1937 (Box 132)
  - Mrs. Douglas Southall Freeman, 1925-1930 (Box 132)
  - Mrs. Douglas Southall Freeman, 1933 (Box 132)
  - Mrs. Douglas Southall Freeman, 1934 (Box 132)
  - Mrs. Douglas Southall Freeman, 1935 (Box 132)
  - Mrs. Douglas Southall Freeman, 1936 (Box 132)
  - Mrs. Douglas Southall Freeman, 1937 - 1939 (Box 132)
  - Mrs. Douglas Southall Freeman, 1945, 1954 and n.d. (Box 132)
  - Mrs. Douglas Southall Place cards - n.d. (Box 132)
  - Letters from Mary Tyler Freeman Cheek, Anne Ballard Freeman, Adler James, Douglas Freeman - 1924 -1929, n.d. (Box 132)
  - Dr. and Mrs. Douglas Southall Freeman, letters from Mary Tyler Freeman Cheek, 1930-1932 (Box 132)
  - Dr. and Mrs. Douglas Southall Freeman, letters from Mary Tyler Freeman Cheek, 1933- 1937 (Box 132)
  - Dr. and Mrs. Douglas Southall Freeman, letters from Mary Tyler Freeman Cheek, 1938- 1942 (Box 132)
  - Dr. and Mrs. Douglas Southall Freeman, letters from Mary Tyler Freeman Cheek, 1943- 1944 (Box 132)
  - Dr. and Mrs. Douglas Southall Freeman, letters from Mary Tyler Freeman Cheek, 1945- 1946 (Box 132)
  - Mrs. Douglas Southall Freeman, Letters from Mary Tyler Freeman Cheek, 1947 - 1951 (Box 132)
  - Mrs. Douglas Southall Freeman, Letters from Mary Tyler Freeman Cheek, 1953 (June 30- July 31) (Box 132)
  - Mrs. Douglas Southall Freeman, Letters from Mary Tyler Freeman Cheek, 1953 (August - September) (Box 132)
  - Mrs. Douglas Southall Freeman, Letters from Mary Tyler Freeman Cheek, 1956 - 1965 (Box 132)
  - Mrs. Douglas Southall Freeman, Letters from Mary Tyler Freeman Cheek,1968 - 1969 (Box 132)
  - Mrs. Douglas Southall Freeman, Letters from Mary Tyler Freeman Cheek,1974 and n.d. (Box 132)
  - Douglas Southall Freeman - Requests for permission to quote from his writings - n.d (Box 132)
  - (Aunt) Florence Freeman - 1917 (Box 132)
  - James Douglas Freeman - 1930 -1934, n. d. (Box 132)
  - Freeman Home - Westbourne - n.d. (Box 132)
  - Wedding to Leslie Cheek, Jr. - Invitation List - 1939 (Box 132)
  - Wedding to Leslie Cheek, Jr. - Planning and preparations - 1939 (Box 132)
  - Wedding to Leslie Cheek, Jr. - Responses to announcement and invitations, gift closures - 1939 (Box 132)
  - Wedding to Leslie Cheek, Jr. - Wedding, Reception, Newspaper announcement, .n.d. surrounding Festivities - 1939 (Box 132)
  - Wedding List Invitation, 1939 (Box 132)